Guide to the George Yuzawa Papers TAM.442
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I: Early Life through World War II, 1908-2004
  - War Relocation Authority: Correspondence: E. M. Rowalt (Deputy Director) to Kimiko Yuzawa (re: repatriation to Japan), Jan 14, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - War Relocation Authority: Correspondence: Jacob Gerrild (Counselor, Public Welfare Section) to James T. Yuzawa, Jun 29, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - War Relocation Authority: First Quarterly Report, Mar 18, 1942-Jun 30, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - War Relocation Authority: Information and Regulations re: Repatriation to Japan, [1940s] (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - War Relocation Authority: Information re: "What Relocators Need to Know and What Evacuees Need to Know to Encourage Them to Relocate", [1940s] (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - War Relocation Authority: Message from WRA Director re: Final Phase of Relocation Program and Closing of Centers, [1945-1946] (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - War Relocation Authority: Public Welfare Section Advisory Committee: Meeting Minutes and Correspondence, Nov 18, 1943-Aug 2, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - War Relocation Authority: Questionnaires to be Filled Out by Relocatees, [1940s] (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - War Relocation Authority: Records on George Yuzawa (copies of medical records, travel requests, references), 1942-1988 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - War Relocation Authority: Records on George Yuzawa: Property Storage and Transportation, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - War Relocation Authority: Relocation Advisory Board: Meeting Minutes and List of Committees and Members, Dec 1943 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - War Relocation Authority: Request for Transportation of Property to Amache, Colorado (made by George Yuzawa), [1942] (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - War Relocation Authority: Resettlement Information Bureau: Flow Chart of Services and Benefits, [1940s] (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - War Relocation Authority: Summary Assessment of Hattori Family at Granada Relocation Center, May 19, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - YMCA of Los Angeles: Correspondence: James W. McCandless to George Yuzawa, Apr 24, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - YMCA of Los Angeles: Correspondence: Masao W. Sato to Japanese American YMCA Fellows (re: mass forced removal), Mar 18, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - YMCA of Los Angeles and Southern California Japanese Athletic Union, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Yuzawa, James T.: Declaration of Intent to Travel, Aug 23, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Yuzawa, James T.: Declaration of Intention Filed With Immigration and Naturalization Service, Feb 7, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Yuzawa, James T.: Letters of Reference from WRA Officers at Amache, Colorado, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Yuzawa, James T.: Scrapbook of Clippings re: World War II, 1944-1953 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Yuzawa, James T.: Spiral Composition Book, [1944] (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Yuzawa, James T. and Bun Yuzawa: Correspondence, 1942-1944 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Yuzawa, James T., Bun, and Chieko Yuzawa: Personal Documents, 1942-1944 (Box 1, Folder 81)
- Series II: Post World War II, 1938-2009
  Series consists of meeting minutes, financial reports, correspondence, event programs, flyers, newsletters, and clippings documenting Yuzawa's activist work within the Japanese and Asian American community in New York from the 1970s to 2000s. The series is organized into seven subseries, each devoted to campaigns or organizations in which Yuzawa took an active part.
  - Subseries A: Redress Campaign and Remembrance, and Japanese American Military Service Memorials, 1972-2009
    Subseries A documents the legislative struggle in the 1980s to secure reparations and official apology from the U.S. government for Japanese Americans incarcerated during WWII, as well as materials regarding Japanese American World War II veterans. Redress and reparations efforts are documented through letters in support of and testimonies given at, summary explanations of laws, newsletters, newspaper clippings as well as flyers and other ephemera advertising workshops, films and other events designed to educate and build collective remembrance of incarceration and support for the Redress Movement. Victory in the campaign is documented through copies of George and Kimi Yuzawa's Redress checks, programs to community Redress celebrations, and photographs of Ronald Reagan signing the 1988 Civil Liberties Act (originals located in Series V: Photographs and Artwork). Materials on Japanese American WWII veterans and their military service consists of newsletters, correspondence and event programs from the Go For Broke Foundation, National Japanese American Memorial Foundation, JANM and other institutions hosting events and erecting memorials commemorating the service of Japanese Americans in the armed forces. Also included are recent clippings that Yuzawa collected about Japanese American WWII veterans.
    - Sub-subseries AI: Redress Campaign and World War II Remembrance, 1975-2009
      Sub-subseries AI: Redress Campaign and World War II Remembrance documents the legislative struggle in the 1980s to secure reparations and official apology from the U.S. government for Japanese Americans incarcerated during WWII. These efforts are documented through letters in support of and testimonies given at, summary explanations of laws, newsletters, newspaper clippings as well as flyers and other ephemera advertising workshops, films and other events designed to educate and build collective remembrance of incarceration and support for the Redress Movement. Victory in the campaign is documented through copies of George and Kimi Yuzawa's Redress checks, programs to community Redress celebrations, and photographs of Ronald Reagan signing the 1988 Civil Liberties Act (originals located in Series V: Photographs and Artwork).
      - General (correspondence, clippings), 1975-2001 (Box 1, Folder 81A)
      - Amache Memorial Dedication and Reunion: Programs, Correspondence and Clippings, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 82)
      - "America's Japanese Internment and its Transgenerational Impact" (student paper by Scarlet W. St. James), [1990s] (Box 1, Folder 83)
      - Brief by Bay Area Attorneys for Redress on Selected Constitutional Issues, undated (Box 1, Folder 84)
      - Campaign for Justice: Redress Now for Japanese Latin Americans: Call for Letters Urging President Clinton to Act, Apr 1998 (Box 1, Folder 85)
      - Clippings re: Day of Remembrance, Internment and Redress (sent to George Yuzawa by Shosuke Sasaki), Nov 1978 (Box 1, Folder 86)
      - Clippings re: Redress, 1972-1981 (Box 1, Folder 87)
      - Clippings and Newsletters re: Redress, 1981-1998 (Box 1, Folder 88)
      - Clippings re: Remembering JA Internment, 1973-2009 (Box 1, Folder 89)
      - Commission on Wartime Relocation and Internment of Civilians Act (Public Law 96-317), Summary of, [1980s] (Box 1, Folder 90)
      - Commission on Wartime Relocation and Internment of Civilians Hearing in New York: East Coast Japanese Americans for Redress: Correspondence, Flyer and Press Release, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 91)
      - Commission on Wartime Relocation and Internment of Civilians: JAHFA Letter in Support of Hearing in New York, Jun 18, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 92)
      - Commission on Wartime Relocation and Internment of Civilians Hearing in New York: Testimonies, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 93)
      - Commission on Wartime Relocation and Internment of Civilians Hearings in New York and Washington, DC: Agendas, Jul 16, 1981-Nov 23, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 94)
      - Conscience and the Constitution (PBS documentary by Frank Abe): Correspondence and Press Release, Jul 2000-Mar 2003 (Box 1, Folder 95)
      - Correspondence: Garry Oniki to Jimmy Carter (in support of Robert F. Drinan's appointment to Commission on Wartime Relocation and Internment of Civilians), Oct 7, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 96)
      - Correspondence: Jack and Aiko Herzig to Chiyeko Watanabe, Elinor Kajiwara, June Kushino and George Yuzawa, Dec 4, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 97)
      - Hearings on H.R. 4110 (Civil Liberties Act of 1983): Summary Statements, Sep 1984 (Box 1, Folder 98)
      - Hirabayashi v. United States: Court Ruling, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 99)
      - Hohri, William et al v. United States: Petition for Rehearing, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 100)
      - H.R. 442, Testimonies in Opposition to: Department of Justice, Apr 25, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - H.R. 442, Testimonies in Support of: Commission on Wartime Relocation and Internment of Civilians, Apr 28, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - H.R. 442, Testimonies in Support of: JACL-LEC and Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith, Apr 28, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - H.R. 442, Testimonies in Support of: Korematsu Legal Team, May 10, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - H.R. 442, Testimonies in Support of: NCJAR and AALDEF, Apr 28, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - H.R. 442, Testimonies in Support of: NCJAR Cover Letter and List of People Who testified at Hearings, Apr 28, 1986-May 28, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - H.R. 442, Testimonies in Support of: Sala Burton, Daniel K. Inouye and Spark Matsunaga, Apr 28, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - H.R. 442, Testimonies in Support of: Washington Coalition on Redress, American Bar Association and ACLU, Apr 28, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - "Japanese American and Concentration Camp" (essay about George Yuzawa written by Michiyo Nakamura), Feb 11, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 8A)
      - JACL: Call for Support of Civil Liberties Act Amendments of 1992 (HR 4551/S2553), Jul 1992 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - JACL: "...Congress Apologizes on Behalf of the Nation" (newsletter about the Civil Liberties Act), 1988 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - JACL: "Japanese American Incarceration: A Case for Redress" Brochure, [1980s] (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - JACL Speakers' Bureau: Presentation Materials and Thank You Letters, 1989-2001 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - JACL: Redress Question and Answer Fact Sheet, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - JACL: Teacher Training Workshop on Japanese American Internment: Letter and Registration Form, May 1998 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Japanese American Internment and Redress: Brochures, Flyers, Booklets, Clippings, 1974-2002 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - National Council for Japanese American Redress: Newsletters, Sep 1984-Jan 1988 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - National Council for Japanese American Redress: Testimony, Newsletter and Press Release re: William M. Hohri, 1980-2001 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - National Council for Japanese American Redress: Oral History Interview with Karl R. Bendetsen (transcript), 1972-1984 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - New York City Day of Remembrance: Ed Koch Mayoral Proclamation, Feb 19, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - New York City Day of Remembrance Committee: "Honoring Japanese American Veterans of WWII" (commemorative book), 1996 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - New York City Day of Remembrance Committee: Programs and Flyers, 1982-2003 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - Office of Redress Administration: George and Kimiko Yuzawa's Redress Payments, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - Office of Redress Administration: Regulations, Forms, Written Statements, and Press re: Redress, 1980-1988 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - Public Law 96-317 (act to establish Commission on Internment): Summary, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - Redress Celebration Committee: Program for "A New York Community Redress Celebration", Nov 4, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - Redress Workshop at JAUC, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - "A Word Heard for the First Time" (essay written by Shun Shimakata), 1994 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Sub-subseries AII: Japanese American Military Service Memorials, 1992-2008
      Sub-subseries AII: Japanese American Military Service Memorials consists of newsletters, correspondence and event programs from the Go For Broke Foundation, National Japanese American Memorial Foundation, JANM and other institutions hosting events and erecting memorials commemorating the service of Japanese Americans in the armed forces. Also included are recent clippings that Yuzawa collected about Japanese American WWII veterans.
      - 100th/442nd/MIS World War II Memorial Foundation: Fundraising Letter and Brochure, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 28)
      - Clippings re: Japanese American World War II Veterans, 1997-2000 (Box 2, Folder 29)
      - Go For Broke Educational Foundation: Newsletter, Exhibition Brochure, Postcards and Clipping, 1998-2008 (Box 2, Folder 30)
      - JANM National Salute to Japanese American Veterans: Program and Tribute Journal, Nov 1995 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      - Japanese American Korean War Veterans: Newsletter and Robert Wada Speech "From Looking Like the Enemy to Solitude", 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 32)
      - National Constitution Center "We the People Award" to JA World War II Veterans: Program, Invitation and Announcement, Nov 2002 (Box 2, Folder 33)
      - National Japanese American Memorial Foundation: Newsletter, Winter 1999 (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - National Japanese American Memorial Foundation Dedication Ceremonies: Program Booklet, Publicity Release, Nov 2000 (Box 2, Folder 35)
      - National Japanese American Memorial to Patriotism Groundbreaking Ceremony: Brochure and Program, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Subseries B: Japanese American National Museum (JANM), 1984-2000
    Subseries B: Japanese American National Museum (JANM) consists largely of press and information about "America's Concentration Camps," an exhibition about Japanese American incarceration on view at the Ellis Island Immigration Museum between November 11, 1994 and October 15, 1995. Yuzawa served on the board of the New York Committee of JANM which brought the exhibition to Ellis Island and thus had access to documents relating to the exhibition's planning such as internal correspondence and resource binders listing information about docents, community relations and key contacts as well as more public documents such as fact sheets, brochures, press kits and museum visiting information. The series also contains member outreach materials such as campaign reports, museum publications, and information on the museum's opening and expansion. There are also a few files relating to the New York Committee of JANM, including its planning of an exhibit featuring early Issei settlement in the state.
    - "America's Concentration Camps" Exhibition: Clippings, Apr 1998-May 1998 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - "America's Concentration Camps" Exhibition: Correspondence and Memos, Mar 1998-May 1998 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - "America's Concentration Camps" Exhibition: Fact Sheets about Exhibition, [1998] (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - "America's Concentration Camps" Exhibition: Docent List and Memos, Mar 1998-May 1998 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - "America's Concentration Camps" Exhibition: George Yuzawa's Letter of Support for Bringing the Exhibition to Ellis Island Immigration Museum, Dec 1996-May 1998 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - "America's Concentration Camps" Exhibition: Museum Visitor Information and Miscellaneous, Mar 1998-Oct 1998 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - "America's Concentration Camps" Exhibition: Press Kit, Apr 1998 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - "America's Concentration Camps" Exhibition: Programs, Brochures, Postcards and Clippings, 1995-1998 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - "America's Concentration Camps": Exhibition Resource Binder: April Schedule of Events, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - "America's Concentration Camps": Exhibition Resource Binder: Community Relations, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - "America's Concentration Camps": Exhibition Resource Binder: Exhibition Text, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - "America's Concentration Camps": Exhibition Resource Binder: Key Contacts, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - "America's Concentration Camps": Exhibition Resource Binder: Museum Information, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - "America's Concentration Camps": Exhibition Resource Binder: Press and Marketing, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - "America's Concentration Camps": Exhibition Resource Binder: Public Programs, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - "America's Concentration Camps": Exhibition Resource Binder: Volunteers, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Booklet Celebrating JANM's Opening, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Clippings re: JANM's Opening, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Construction of JANM's New Expansion Pavilion: Letter to Supporters, Jun 1998 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Correspondence (general), 1991-1997 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Event Calendars, Programs, Flyers and Invitations, 1992-1999 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - "Issei Pioneers in Oregon" Traveling Exhibit: Grant Proposal, Dec 1985 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - JANM and American Jewish Committee Joint Statements re: Use of Term "Concentration Camps", Mar 1998 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Japanese American National Museum Bulletins (newsletters), 1988-1993 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Japanese American National Museum Magazine, Spring 2000 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Japanese American National Museum Quarterly, 1994-1998 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - List of Board of Trustees and Staff, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Member Outreach and Campaign Reports, 1990-1992 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - New York Advisory Council Memo re: JANM's Mission/Vision, May 1999 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - New York Committee of JANM: Correspondence (with Board of Trustees Minutes), Nov 1990-Jun 1994 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - New York Committee of JANM: New York Project: Correspondence and Attachments, Mar 1992-Apr 1994 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - New York Committee of JANM: New York Project: Correspondence and Attachments re: Issei Pioneer Exhibit, Jan 1990-Sep 1992 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - New York Committee of JANM: Grant Proposal (draft), undated (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Oral History Instructions, Sample Interview and Questions, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Subseries C: Asian American Media Monitoring, 1952-2006
    Subseries C: Asian American Media Monitoring documents the campaigns that George Yuzawa, Kazu Iijima, Aiko Herzig Yoshinaga and other activists who later founded Asian Americans for Fair Media conducted during the 1970s and 1980s against racially offensive representations of Asian Americans in the media. The campaigns—which include protests against designer Kenzo Takada's use of the trademark "JAP" on his clothing labels, the ILGWU's "Made in Japan" poster scapegoating Japan for Americans' loss of jobs, and the use of the term "Jap" in newspapers and broadcasts—are largely documented through correspondence and clippings but also through a few flyers, press releases, notes and legal documents.
    - Asian Americans for Fair Media: The Asian Image in the United States (handbook and circulated draft), 1973 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Asian Americans for Fair Media: Correspondence and Clippings, Sep 1972-Jun 1975 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Asian Americans for Fair Media: Correspondence and Clippings, Jul 1972-Mar 1982 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Asian Americans for Fair Media: Founder(s) File, 1969-1987 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Campaign against ILGWU "Made in Japan" Poster: Asian Americans for Action: Correspondence, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Campaign against ILGWU "Made in Japan" Poster: Asian Americans for Action: Picket Planning Committee Working Papers, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Campaign against ILGWU "Made in Japan" Poster: Asian Americans for Action: Signed Petition, Sep 1972-Oct 1972 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Campaign against ILGWU "Made in Japan" Poster: Clippings, Aug 1972-Nov 1972 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Campaign against ILGWU "Made in Japan" Poster: Poster (copies of), [1970s] (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Campaign against John J. Wilson's Slur on Senator Daniel K. Inouye's Ancestry: Clippings, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Campaign against John J. Wilson's Slur on Senator Daniel K. Inouye's Ancestry: Letters of Protest, Aug 1973 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Campaign against Kenzo Takada's Use of Trademark "J.A.P.": Anti-Kenzo Campaign Package (includes correspondence and clippings), 1978 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Campaign against Kenzo Takada's Use of Trademark "J.A.P.": "Boycott J.A.P. !!" Leaflets, [1970s] (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Campaign against Kenzo Takada's Use of Trademark "J.A.P.": Clippings, 1971-1978 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Campaign against Kenzo Takada's Use of Trademark "J.A.P.": Clippings (in Japanese), 1972 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Campaign against Kenzo Takada's Use of Trademark "J.A.P.": Clippings (mostly from New York Nichibei), 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Campaign against Kenzo Takada's Use of Trademark "J.A.P.": Clippings of Advertisements, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Campaign against Kenzo Takada's Use of Trademark "J.A.P.": Clippings re: Butterick Fashion Marketing Company, Aug 1972-Sep 1972 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Campaign against Kenzo Takada's Use of Trademark "J.A.P.": Clippings re: Exclusion of Kenzo in Nisei Week Festival Fashion Show, Jul 1972 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Campaign against Kenzo Takada's Use of Trademark "J.A.P.": Correspondence, 1971-1976 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Campaign against Kenzo Takada's Use of Trademark "J.A.P.": Correspondence: Butterick Fashion Marketing Company, 1972-1975 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Campaign against Kenzo Takada's Use of Trademark "J.A.P.": Correspondence: Consulate General of Japan, Jul 1971-Jul 1972 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Campaign against Kenzo Takada's Use of Trademark "J.A.P.": Correspondence: Eleanor Holmes Norton to William Fine, Jun 1, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Campaign against Kenzo Takada's Use of Trademark "J.A.P.": Correspondence: Glenn Omatsu to David Ushio, May 30, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Campaign against Kenzo Takada's Use of Trademark "J.A.P.": Correspondence: George Yuzawa to Harry A. Murray, Sep 15, 1971-Jul 26, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Campaign against Kenzo Takada's Use of Trademark "J.A.P.": Correspondence: Jewish Conciliation Board of America, Jul 7, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Campaign against Kenzo Takada's Use of Trademark "J.A.P.": Correspondence: (Mrs.) Kazu Obayashi to Spark Matsunaga, Jul 20, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Campaign against Kenzo Takada's Use of Trademark "J.A.P.": Correspondence: Manuel Diaz to George Yuzawa, Jun 9, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Campaign against Kenzo Takada's Use of Trademark "J.A.P.": Correspondence: Moonray Kojima to Muriel Silverberg, Jun 3, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Campaign against Kenzo Takada's Use of Trademark "J.A.P.": Correspondence re: Exclusion of Kenzo Takada in Nisei Week Festival Fashion Show, Jul 1972 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Campaign against Kenzo Takada's Use of Trademark "J.A.P.": Correspondence: Suki Ports to Daniel K. Inouye, Aug 1, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Campaign against Kenzo Takada's Use of Trademark "J.A.P.": Correspondence: Suki Ports to Patsy Mink, Jul 29, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Campaign against Kenzo Takada's Use of Trademark "J.A.P.": Correspondence: Suki Ports to Spark Matsunaga, Aug 1, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Campaign against Kenzo Takada's Use of Trademark "J.A.P.": Correspondence: U.S. Bureau of Customs, Jun 1971 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Campaign against Kenzo Takada's Use of Trademark "J.A.P.": Handwritten Notes, [1970s] (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Campaign against Kenzo Takada's Use of Trademark "J.A.P.": JACL v. Kenzo Takada (affadavit submitted by George Yuzawa), Jun 3, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Campaign against Kenzo Takada's Use of Trademark "J.A.P.": Press Release, Aug 3, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Campaign against Kenzo Takada's Use of Trademark "J.A.P.": Resolution (formal agreement and press announcement), Jul 1972-Aug 1972 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Campaign against Use of Term "Jap": Correspondence, Handwritten Notes and Clippings, 1971-1998 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Campaign against Use of Term "Jap" in Newspapers: Correspondence, Sep 1952-Mar 1981 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Clippings, 1972-2006 (Box 3, Folder 41)